before we start on the theory behind the
在我们开始讨论理想气体定律实验背后的理论之前，
ideal gas law experiment just a quick
只是一个快速
warning that this experiment is quite
警告，这个实验非常
difficult it's designed to help you
困难，它旨在帮助你
practice some of the hardest part of the
练习热主题中最难的部分
thermal concepts of the thermal topic so
热概念，
it's really important that you come well
所以做好充分准备非常重要
prepared to the lab okay
去实验室
this one this is the syringe you'll be
好吧 一个这是您将要使用的注射器，现在您将在
masses on top of it now as you know from
其上放置质量，正如您从物理学 1a 中所知道的，
physics 1a when you paste masses on
当您将质量粘贴到
something there's a weight force so by
有重力的东西上时，通过
placing buttons up here you'll be
将按钮放在这里，您将
exerting a weight force on this plunger
在此柱塞上施加重力
here and you're going to be using this
，您将使用它
to calculate and then you're going to
来计算，然后您将
measure the pressure inside the syringe
测量注射器内的压力
so as hopefully you'll remember the
，希望您能记住
pressure is equal to force over area and
压力等于面积上的力和
this area here is the cross sectional
这个面积 这是 e
area of the syringe so it's the area of
注射器的横截面积，所以这里是这个表面的面积，
this surface here so you like to be able
所以您希望能够
to measure this in the lab because for
在实验室中测量它，因为对于
this syringe you'll be able to measure
这个注射器，您将能够
the volumes and you also use your ruler
测量体积，并且您还可以使用
to measure the height and the volume
尺子测量高度 并且体积
divided by the height is going to give
除以高度将为
you the cross-sectional area for that
您提供该柱塞的横截面积，
plunger so pressure equals force over
因此压力等于
area in this case a force is applied by
面积上的力在这种情况下
the weight so when you add weight you'll
，重量是由重量施加的，因此当您增加重量时
get a change in pressure and that will
，压力会发生变化，并且 这将
equal mg on a where a is a
等于 a 上的毫克，其中 a 是
cross-sectional area now one important
横截面积 现在
thing to remember is that we are in the
要记住的重要一件事是我们在
lab and because the lab is on earth
实验室中，因为实验室在地球
on us so the total pressure experienced
上，所以我们承受的总压力
by the syringe is going to be in
是 注射器将处于
atmospheric pressure which should be 1.0
大气压下，应该是 1.0
1 times 10 to the 5 Pascal's but you'll
1 乘以 10 到 5 帕斯卡，但你
be able to measure it to check that plus
可以测量它来检查它加上
the additional pressure from the weight
来自重力的额外压力，
force so in addition to this you're
所以除此之外你
going to be using the ideal gas law
将 使用理想气体定律
which tells us that PV is equal to n R P
wh  ich 告诉我们 PV 等于 n R P
now in this first part of the experiment
现在在实验的第一部分中，
you're going to fill the syringe up to
您要将注射器填充到
some initial volume and then you're not
某个初始体积，然后
going to let the air in or out after
在完成后不要让空气进出
you've done that so because the air is
那是因为空气
not going in or out and the number of
不会进出，
moles will remain constant R the gas
摩尔数将保持不变 R 气体
constant is just a constant and with the
常数只是一个常数，随着
temperature for this part you're
这部分的温度，你
actually going to wait for the syringe
实际上要等待注射器
to come to thermal equilibrium with the
达到热平衡
after you add each of the masses so the
添加每个质量之后的环境，所以
temperature is actually going to be
温度实际上也是
constant as well it's just going to be
恒定的，它
the room temperature so we thought every
只是室温，所以我们认为
time here is constant so this will allow
这里的每次都是恒定的，所以这将允许
us to use that PV is constant and so the
我们使用 PV 是恒定的，所以
initial pressure times the initial
初始压力乘以初始
volume is going to equal any final
体积将等于任何最终
pressure times final volume so you'll be
压力乘以最终体积，所以你将
making use of this equation in the first
在实验的前半部分使用这个等式，这
the theory that you're going to need for
就是你在
Part 1
第 1 部分
in part two of this experiment you're
中需要的理论 第二部分 进行实验，您
going to be taking the gas inside the
将通过一个循环将注射器内的气体
syringe through a cycle so first you're
吸入，因此首先您
going to be doing an adiabatic
将进行绝热
compression then you'll have an iso
压缩，然后您将进行等
volumetric process where it's going to
体积过程，它将
be coming to thermal equilibrium with
与房间达到热平衡，
the room and then you're going to do an
并且 然后你要做一个
isothermal expansion where it's slowly
等温膨胀，它会
going to come back up to its initial
慢慢恢复到它的初始
volume so in order to understand what's
体积，所以为了
going on there you're going to need to
了解那里发生了什么，你需要
understand what what each of the terms
了解我们刚刚提到的每个术语是什么
that we've just used means so let's go
used 意味着让我们来看看
through them and adiabatic process
它们，绝热过程
is one in which no heat is transferred
是一种没有热量传递的过程，
so q is equal to zero now how you're
所以 q 等于 0 现在你
going to achieve this in the lab is
将如何在实验室中实现这一点是
you're going to compress it very quickly
你将很快压缩它，
so if you do something quickly then
所以如果你这样做 很快就
there's no time for the heat to be
没有时间传递热量了
transferred and so Q is equal to zero
，所以
now for an adiabatic process the gas
对于绝热过程
also a beta closure and PV to the gamma
，现在 Q
is equal to the constant so you would
等于 0
equal to CP on TV the specific heat at
等于吨 o 电视上的 CP
constant pressure and the specific heat
恒定压力下的比
at constant volume and that is equal to
热和恒定体积下的比热等于
S Plus 2 on F where F is the number of
F 上的 S 加 2 其中 F 是
degrees of freedom now inside this
现在这个注射器内的自由度数
I've just got air because I've just
我刚刚得到空气，因为我已经
filled it up from the lab and air is
刚从实验室把它填满，空气
mainly comprised of nitrogen n2 and
主要由氮 n2 和
oxygen o2 so an it's basically a
氧 o2 组成，所以它基本上是一种
diatomic ideal gas so as you hopefully
双原子理想气体，所以你希望
know and diatomic gas at room
知道，室温下的双原子气体
temperature has five degrees of freedom
有五个自由度
it's got three translational degrees of
它有三个平移
freedom and two rotational degrees of
自由度和 两个旋转自由度，
freedom so at room temperature we've got
所以在室温下，我们得到
X is equal to five at room temperature
X 在室温和压力下等于 5，
and pressure so this tells us that gamma
所以这告诉我们，在室温下，伽马
is equal to seven on five or 1.4 for air
等于 5 上的 7 或 1.4，
at room temperature so you'll be using
所以你将使用
this equation in the lab to describe
这个方程 在实验室中描述
that idea basic process now another
这个想法 基本过程 现在
process that you're going to be looking
你将
at in this cycle is an isothermal
在这个循环中看到的另一个过程是等温
expansion
膨胀
now all of part one was isothermal
现在所有第一部分都是等温的，
because we were giving it time to come
因为我们给它时间来
to thermal equilibrium with the
达到热平衡 rium 与
surroundings so isothermal processes
周围环境，所以等温过程
tend to be slow because this allows time
往往很慢，因为这
for the heat to be transferred and for
允许热量传递和
everything to reach the surrounding
一切达到周围
temperature so the equations that we
温度的时间，所以我们
have that explain or describe isothermal
有解释或描述等温
processes are we've got that there's no
过程的方程是我们得到的，没有
changing temperature and so we know that
变化 温度，所以我们
the constant internal energy is given by
知道恒定的内能是由
F over two and our delta T and the
F 超过 2 和我们的 delta T 给出的，
temperature is not changing that is
温度没有变化，
going to be no change in the internal
现在内能不会改变
energy now the other thing that we know
另一件事，我们
that we showed in part one was that PV
知道我们在第一部分展示了 是 PV
is equal to constant and that's because
等于常数，那是因为
n iron teeth are all not changing so
n 个铁齿都没有变化，所以
this is constant so the final process
这是常数，所以
you're going to be doing in your cycle
你在循环中要做的最后一个过程
is an ISO volumetric process where
是一个 ISO 体积过程，
you're just going to be letting it come
你只是让它 在
surroundings without changing the volume
不改变体积的情况下与周围环境达到热平衡
the ISO volumetric
ISO
is one in which the change in volume is
体积是其中体积变化
equal to zero and as we're not changing
等于 0 并且因为我们没有
the volume we're not doing any work on
改变体积，所以我们是 n 没有对注射器内部的间隙做任何工作
the gap inside that syringe and so for
，因此对于
isovolumetric processes the work is
等容过程，工作
equal to zero and looking at the ideal
等于零，并且查看理想
gas law the V is constant so the equals
气体定律，V 是恒定的，因此等于
constant which is equal to NRT over the
常数，等于 NRT 在
pressure just rearranging the ideal gas
压力上只是重新排列理想气体
law so NR p on pressure is constant so
定律 所以压力上的 NR p 是恒定的，所以
when you've measured everything for your
当你测量了循环的所有内容时，
cycle your volumes your temperatures and
你的体积、温度
your pressures you're going to be
和压力，你将
looking at how the first law of
看到热力学第一定律
thermodynamics applies in this case so
在这种情况下是如何应用的，所以
you'll also need to know your first law
你还需要知道 你的第一
which is just that the change in the
定律就是
internal energy is equal to the heat
内部能量的变化等于
transferred into the system plus the
传递到系统中的热量加上系统上
work done on the system so you'll be
所做的功，所以你将把它
applying this to these different cases
应用于这些不同的
here do you know what the to zero in the
情况，你知道什么是零
isothermal process we know that the
等温过程，我们知道
change in internal energy is 0 and in
内能的变化是 0，
the isovolumetric process we know that
在等容过程中，我们
the work is zero
知道功为零，
so for this experiment you're going to
所以对于这个实验，你
need a ruler for measuring the height of
需要一把尺子来测量
your syringe and the pencil for drawing
注射器的高度和 d 用于绘制循环图的铅笔，
the graph of the cycle so please
因此请
remember to bring a ruler and a pencil
记住在此实验期间将尺子和铅笔
to the lab with you during this
带到实验室，您将在
syringe here
此处使用此注射器，
you can read the volumes of the size of
您可以在此处读取注射器尺寸的体积
the syringe at the bottom of the syringe
注射器底部
there's a temperature sensor
有一个温度
the temperature sensor is a thermocouple
传感器 温度传感器是一个热电偶
device which does take a very small
装置，它确实需要很
increment of time to come to thermal
短的时间才能
equilibrium with the surroundings so
与周围环境达到热平衡，所以
just keep that in mind when you are
在测量温度时请记住，
measuring the temperature it's not an
它不是
instantaneous temperature it does take a
瞬时温度 读取温度确实需要
lot less than a second a very small
不到一秒的时间非常小
increment of time to read off the
的时间增量，
temperature so you're not actually going
因此您现在
to be able to measure the absolute
实际上无法测量绝对
maximum temperature now to connect the
最高温度来连接
temperature sensor you've got a cord at
温度传感器，您有一根
the bottom of the syringe and you're
电线 注射器底部，您
just going to plug that into this
只需将其插入此
passport device and this will now be
护照设备，现在将
logging the temperature at the bottom of
记录该注射器底部的温度，
that syringe now this syringe also has a
现在该注射器也有一个
pressure sensor so that's connected to
压力传感器，所以它
the passport device through this tube
通过这个管子连接到护照设备
here now this device has a screw and
现在这个设备有一个螺丝和
click mechanism it's really important
点击机制
that you don't pull and yank this
，你不要在这里拉和拉这个
connector here because that is going to
连接器非常重要，因为这会
break the syringe so to connect this to
破坏注射器，所以将它连接
the passport device you just put it on
到 护照装置，您只需将其戴上
and then screw it round and you'll hear
，然后将其拧紧，您会
a little click and it's then locked into
听到一点咔哒声，然后将其锁定
place so that's a pressure sensor that
到位，这是一个压力传感器，
when you're putting air into or out of
当您将空气注入或
the syringe you need to have this
流出注射器时，您需要有这个
pressure sensor disconnected so that the
压力 传感器断开连接，这样
air can flow through it freely through
空气就可以通过这里的管子自由流过它，
this tube here so once you've connected
所以一旦你把它
this to the passport device you're then
连接到护照设备，
going to need to connect the passport
你就需要将护照
device directly to the computer so it's
设备直接连接到电脑上，所以它
just got a USB cord that you will be
只有一根 USB 线 您将
plugging into the computer so let's have
插入计算机，所以
a look now what happens when we plug it
现在让我们看看当我们将其插入计算机时会发生什么，
into the computer so that we can get
以便我们
the software all set up and ready to
可以设置所有软件并准备好为
record for this experiment you're going
您将要进行的这个实验进行记录
to be using the capstone software you
使用 capstone 软件
open it up from the dock down the bottom
从底部的底座打开它，
the icon is like a little pyramid so
图标就像一个小金字塔，所以
click on that to open it and then you'll
点击它打开它，然后你
need to open the ideal gas law template
需要
by going open experiment and choosing
通过打开实验并
the ideal gas law from within the
选择理想气体来打开理想气体定律模板
done that you should see an absolute
完成后，您应该在屏幕上看到绝对
pressure versus time graph and
压力与时间的关系图和
temperature versus time graph on your
温度与时间的关系图。
screen when you're ready to record data
当您准备好记录数据时，
you'll hit the little red record button
您将按下红色的小记录
down in the bottom left-hand corner so
按钮 现在
let's see how to get ready to record
让我们看看如何准备记录
that data now so for Part one of the
该数据，因此对于实验的第一部分，
experiment you're going to need 60
您将需要
milliliters of air inside the syringe so
注射器内有 60 毫升空气，因此
we'll make sure that the pressure sensor
我们将确保压力传感器
is disconnected pull the plunger up - it
已断开连接 向上拉柱塞 - 它的大小为
measures 60 milliliters and then connect
60 毫升，然后
the pressure cents off back to the
将压力美分连接回
syringe now we're going to be placing
注射器现在我们将
masses on this syringe so we need the
在这个注射器上放置质量，所以我们需要
syringe to be nice and stationary so
注射器是好的和静止的，
with the both head and clamp clamp the
所以头部和 cl  amp 夹住
syringe with the base of the syringe
注射器，注射器底部
flat on the cork map you don't need to
平放在软木塞图上，你不需要把
clamp it too tightly this is just to
它夹得太紧，这只是为了
provide a bit of stability so that it
提供一点稳定性，这样它就
doesn't wobble about as we're taking the
不会在我们现在进行
measurements now before we start with
测量时晃动 在我们开始
not going to need to get some initial
之前不需要进行一些初始
measurements so that we know what the
测量，以便我们知道
atmospheric pressure or at least the
大气压或至少
pressure inside that syringe are so you
注射器内的压力是多少，这样
can now press the collect button on your
您现在可以按下计算机上的收集按钮
computer or the Start button and this
或开始按钮，这
will start collecting the data so now
将开始收集 数据所以
what we're going to do is we're going to
现在我们要做的是我们将
press paste some masses on top of the
在注射器顶部粘贴一些物质
syringe to start applying that force and
以开始施加该力并
changing the pressure so it's to start
改变压力所以
with we're going to add one and a half
首先我们将添加一个半
kilos to the syringe
公斤到注射器，
so we're going to need the 500 gram mass
所以我们将需要 500 克的质量
hold off with two of these 500 gram
，并在上面放置两个 500 克的
masses on it now with this experiment
质量，现在在这个实验
it's really important that everything is
中，所有东西都
carefully aligned vertically we don't
仔细垂直对齐非常重要，我们不
want these masses applying any side
希望这些质量应用任何侧
woods force onto the syringe we want
木 力量 到注射器上，我们希望
everything vertically up and down and
所有东西都垂直上下，
again with this clamp at the top this is
然后再用顶部的夹子，这
not actually to hold these masses it's
实际上并不是为了固定这些质量，
just to provide some stability and stop
只是为了提供一些稳定性并阻止
them falling off the clamp so this is
它们从夹子上掉下来，所以它
just resting on the top there so that
只是放在顶部，这样
the entire 1.5 kilograms is applying a
整个 1.5 公斤都在
weight force downwards so just make sure
向下施加重力，所以只要
that everything is nicely aligned
确保一切都很好地垂直对齐，
vertically now it's going to take a very
现在
short time for this syringe to come to
这个注射器需要很短的时间才能
thermal equilibrium with the room
与室温达到热平衡
temperature and you'll be able to see
，你将能够看到
when that has happened on your
什么时候 这发生在你的
temperature graph because you're going
温度图上，因为
to get a little blip when you put the
当你把质量放在上面时你会得到一点点
masses on and then it's going to return
，然后它会
nicely to the room temperature so those
很好地恢复到室温，所以这些
doesn't be the measurement that you'll
不是你想要的测量
want to be taking for this part you can
值 对于这部分，您可以
later but as you're going it's really
稍后测量压力和温度，但是在您进行操作时
important that you read the volumes off
，读取
the sides of the syringe and record
注射器侧面的体积并将
these next to the masses in the book so
这些记录在质量旁边非常重要 书，所以
when I've got 1.5 kilograms on there my
当我有 1.5 公斤时，我的
syringe is measuring 49 milliliters so I
注射器测量为 49 毫升，所以我
would write that down so once you've
会写下来，所以一旦你
recorded the volume and it's returned to
记录了体积并且它返回到
their moral ibrahim you can add the next
他们的道德易卜拉欣，你可以添加下一个
mass on you'll get a little blip in the
质量你会得到一个
temperature again just wait until it
温度再次出现一点点，只是等到它
returns to the room temperature because
恢复到室温，因为
remember if we're making the assumption
请记住，如果我们
that this is isothermal at this point
假设此时这是等温的
and then once it's returned to the room
，然后一旦它恢复到
temperature read off the volume in my
室温，在我的情况下读取体积为
case that's 46 milliliters and record
46 毫升 并
that in your book you keep on doing this
记录在你的书中你继续这样做
until all the masses have been added to
直到所有的质量都被添加到
your system you
你的系统中
at time to return to thermal equilibrium
你要回到热平衡
and recording the volume every time
并且每次记录体积
now that you've recorded your data it's
现在你已经记录了你的数据是
time to analyze it so you should have
时候分析它所以你
graphs on the screen which look a lot
屏幕上应该有图表，
like this now what we need to do is get
现在看起来很像这样我们需要做的是获取
the mean value of the pressure in each
每个区域的压力平均值，
and measure the temperature when once
并在
it's recur return to thermal equilibrium
它再次返回到热 e 时测量温度
as well so to do that it gives little
quilibrium 也这样做，它提供了一个小
highlighter button and then we need to
荧光笔按钮，然后我们需要
adjust the size of the box and then
调整框的大小，然后
we'll drag it to the area that we're
我们将它拖到我们感兴趣的区域，
interested in so this here shows me the
所以这里向我展示
initial pressure this was before I added
了之前的初始压力 我添加了
any masses so to get the value for that
任何质量，以便获得它的值，
I then once I've put my box over it I
然后一旦我把我的盒子放在它上面，我
hit the little Sigma button which gives
点击了小西格玛按钮，它给了
me the statistics so this will tell me
我统计数据，所以这将告诉我
if I want but what I'm interested in is
如果我愿意我可以选择其他统计数据的平均值但是什么 我感兴趣的
the mean so what I can do is I could
是平均值，所以我可以做的是我可以
move this box around to each of these
将这个盒子移动到每个
places or I can create a new box
地方，或者我可以
whichever one you prefer for each region
为每个区域创建一个你喜欢的新盒子，
so now it's got the box we put it on
所以现在它有了我们放在这里的盒子
here and this is when I added 1.5
这是我增加了 1.5
kilograms so let's just get it to
公斤的时候，所以让我们让它达到
thermal equilibrium and then hit the
热平衡，然后点击
statistics button for that box and it
那个盒子的统计按钮，它
tells me that the mean is 124 point
告诉我平均值是 124 点
eight so I would then record that in my
8，所以我会在我的
box next to the in my book sorry next to
盒子旁边的盒子里记录它 书对不起旁边
the one point five kilograms now I just
的一点五公斤现在我
do need to check this we come to a
只需要 检查
somewhat query on each time I expect
一下，每次我希望
these temperatures to be the same so I
这些温度相同时，我们都会进行一些查询，所以我
create the boxes over here as well
在这里创建了盒子，这里是
here's the temperature before I added
我添加任何质量之前的温度，
any masses so get the statistics on that
所以得到统计数据，
and then you can see the blip when I
然后你可以看到当 我
added the masses what I'm interested in
添加了我感兴趣的
is a bit after it's returned to thermal
是在它恢复到热
equilibrium so that shows this box and
平衡之后的质量，以便显示这个盒子
put it there and just make it fit you
并将它放在那里并让它适合你
know get the statistics for that box
知道得到那个盒子的统计数据
thirty point three five so you can see
30 点 3 5 以便你可以看到
it is returning to pretty much the same
它 正在恢复到几乎与预期相同的
temperature like it was meant to so fill
温度，因此请
out that table in your book and then you
在书中填写该表，然后您
can answer the questions
可以回答
about what happened in part two of this
有关本实验第二部分中发生的事情的问题，
experiment you're going to be taking the
您将
air inside the cylinder through a cycle
通过气缸内的空气 一个循环，
so to do this you're going to need to
所以要做到这一点，你需要
push down quickly so remove the syringe
快速向下推，所以
from the clamp now for this part you're
现在从夹子上取下注射器，这部分
going to need 40 milliliters of air in
你需要注射器中的 40 毫升空气，
the syringe so remember to change the
所以记得改变
volume of the air you need to disconnect
你的空气量 需要
the pressure sensor compress the syringe
断开压力传感器，将注射器压缩
down to 40 milliliters and then put the
到 40 毫升，然后将
pressure sensor back in so now it's all
压力传感器放回原处，所以现在它全部
connected up at 40 milliliters what
连接到 40 毫升，
you're going to do is an adiabatic
你要做的是绝热
compression so a quick compression
压缩，所以你要快速压缩
while it comes to thermal equilibrium
当它
with the surrounds and then you're going
与周围环境达到热平衡时将其按住，然后您
to very slowly let it come back up and
将非常缓慢地让它恢复，
while you're doing that you're going to
当您这样做时，您将
try and keep the temperature constant so
尝试保持温度恒定，因此
before you start the process remember to
在您开始之前 过程记得
collect the data press start then quick
收集数据按开始然后快速
compression hold it there while it comes
压缩将其保持在那里，同时
to thermal equilibrium which you will
达到热平衡，您将
see on your temperature graph it will
在温度图上看到它会
level off and go horizontal once it's
趋于平稳并在水平后变为
horizontal let it go up very slowly
水平让它非常缓慢地上升，
trying to keep the temperature line as
试图保持温度线
if you'd end up returning to the 40
如果你最终回到开始时的 40
milliliters as it started
毫升，尽可能水平